[Edcouch] First Baptist Church records, Inclusive: 1941-1974, undated, Bulk: 1949-1952
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
[Edcouch] First Baptist Church records
Inclusive: 1941-1974, undated, Bulk: 1949-1952
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
118
Edcouch First Baptist Church
1 document box
The [Edcouch] First Baptist Church records consist of correspondence and literary manuscripts pertaining to administrative operations of the church.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Unknown.
Biography/Profile
[Edcouch] First Baptist Church, originally named Los Indios Baptist Church, was organized during the summer of 1924 in Los Indios, Texas. In 1925 June, after church member Silas Rohr donated a plot of land to the church, the church moved to a new location and changed its name to Adams Tract Baptist Church. In 1927 February the church relocated to a lot in the newly formed and nearby townsite of Edcouch and again changed its name to First Baptist Church of Edcouch. In 1929 March, First Baptist Church of Edcouch licensed its first missionary, a young man named E. Paul Carroll. By 1963, First Baptist Church of Edcouch was one of two churches in the town.
Scope and Content
The [Edcouch] First Baptist Church records begin in 1941 and end in 1974. The correspondence series is the largest in the collection and mostly consists of letters regarding church membership from 1949 to 1952. Also included are documents from a five-year progress plan from the 1950s and a flyer advertising the fiftieth anniversary of the organization of the church.
Arrangement
The [Edcouch] First Baptist Church recordswere organized with folder titles and numbers prior to this finding aid, with inventories of the collection and a finding aid. Most of the folder titles already existing were kept.
Currently, the [Edcouch] First Baptist Church records are arranged in two series: I. Correspondence, II. Literary Productions.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 118. Acquired 1974-09-04
Related Resources
Related collection materials
First Baptist Church, Edcouch, Texas [microform] contains minutes for the church's business sessions from 1924 to 1998, and membership rolls and related materials from 1928 to 1958.
Related references
Garza, Alicia A. “Edcouch, TX.” The Handbook of Texas Online. Accessed 2013 May 16.
Wade, Dorothy. History of the First Baptist Church of Edcouch, Texas. 1952.
Index Terms
Subjects (Organizations)
First Baptist Church (Edcouch, Tex.) -- History.
Places
Edcouch (Tex.) -- Church history.; Hidalgo County (Tex.) -- Church history.
Subjects
Baptists -- Texas -- Edcouch -- History.; Baptists -- Texas -- Hidalgo County -- History.; Baptists -- Texas.
Genres
Correspondence.
- Correspondence, 1941-1954, undated; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Average.
  Biography/Profile
  This series is the largest in the collection and contains correspondence relating to church membership of First Baptist Church in Edcouch from 1941 to 1954. This series is in average condition.
  - Letters of Recommendation from [Edcouch] First Baptist Church, 1949-1951 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letters of Recommendation to [Edcouch] First Baptist Church, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letters of Recommendation to [Edcouch] First Baptist Church, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letters of Recommendation to [Edcouch] First Baptist Church, 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letters of Recommendation to [Edcouch] First Baptist Church (1 of 2), 1952 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letters of Recommendation to [Edcouch] First Baptist Church (2 of 2), 1952 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Letters of Recommendation to [Edcouch] First Baptist Church, 1952-1954, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Requests for Church Letters from [Edcouch] First Baptist Church, 1949-1952 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Church Letters to [Edcouch] First Baptist Church, 1941-1950 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Church Letters to [Edcouch] First Baptist Church, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Church Letters to [Edcouch] First Baptist Church, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Church Letters to [Edcouch] First Baptist Church (1 of 2), 1952 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Church Letters to [Edcouch] First Baptist Church (2 of 2), 1952 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Literary Productions, 1945-1974, undated; 2
  This series contains documents pertaining to a five-year progress plan for First Baptist Church in Edcouch from the 1950s, a flyer advertising the fiftieth anniversary of the church, and other items. This series is in fair to good condition.
  - General, 1945-1974, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Five-Year Progress Plan, 1954-1957 (Box 1, Folder 15)